Jack Crawford Robertson

Contact Information:

Email: jack@ya-ya.co.uk Phone: 07588502199

Website: jack-robertson.co.uk
Project: maya.jack-robertson.co.uk
Written: written.jack-robertson.co.uk

About Me:

I am a communicator specialising in data-driven storytelling and visual communication. My expertise lies in blending powerful storytelling, data analytics, and engaging visual narratives with effective messaging to simplify complex topics such as climate change, geopolitics, and social sciences. I excel in creating accessible and visually compelling data visualisations using modern web technologies to inspire empathetic understanding.

Experience:

Data Journalist

July 2024 - Present | ICE-HUB

- Led the development of cutting-edge storytelling methods tailored for corporate events.
- Produced an industry-first, web-based interactive research project using Next.js and D3, boosting community engagement by 40%.

Digital Consultant

July 2023 - Present | UK Pollster, UK Water Supplier and the NHS

- Consulted leading UK pollster to design web-based interactive visualisations using D3 and JavaScript, making complex polling data accessible.
- Advised one of the UK's largest water suppliers on integrating Al process to automate, and improve workflows.
- Developed automated workflows using JavaScript for the NHS Mental Health, resulting in improved cross-team understanding within the mental health system.

Designer - Girardot

September 2022 - 2023

- Produced weekly editorial content for The Times, The Week, The Spectator and Condé Nast, honing skills in rapid content production and storytelling.
- Delivered data-driven advertising and visual content for multiple Global Equity Income Funds, utilising tools like Adobe Creative Cloud Excel, and Plotly to increase their value by over 180%.

Event Production - Capgemini Invent

July 2020 - 2021

- Worked with The Faculty on a major Capgemini event in Paris, assisting in event execution and visual design.
- Created iconography and visual assets using Adobe Illustrator and After Effects to enhance the event's visual appeal.

Education:

The Royal College of Art

MA Digital Direction, Archived, 2023 - 2024

• Developed "Maya," a tool for Middle East based NGOs to interpret complex data, utilising advanced data visualisation techniques and web-based technologies such as Next.js and D3.

Central Saint Martins

BA Communication Design, 1st Honours, 2019 - 2022

 Specialised in Graphic Communication Design with a focus on data visualisation and user experience design.

Skills:

- Data Visualisation: React, D3, ObservablePlot, Plotly, ChartJS
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, JavaScript, Next.js
- Mapping Technologies: MapLibre, DeckGL, Leaflet, Mapbox
- Data Management & Analysis: Python, Excel
- Design & Visual Communication: Full Stack Adobe Creative Cloud
- **Project Management:** Agile methodologies, workshop facilitation

Achievements:

- Complexity & Design Award at Central Saint Martins.
- Developed "Maya," an online policy tool aiding NGOs in the MENA region, recognised for its innovative use of data visualisation to secure funding from international donors.